<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A charter of regulations granted to the East-India Company, by Their sacred Majesties King William and Queen Mary, under the Great Seal of England, dated the 28th. of September, 1694</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1689-1694 : William and Mary)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1694</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 39 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A66231</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing W2498B</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R219991</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99831431</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99831431</idno>
            <idno type="VID">35894</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A66231)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 35894)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2121:06)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A charter of regulations granted to the East-India Company, by Their sacred Majesties King William and Queen Mary, under the Great Seal of England, dated the 28th. of September, 1694</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1689-1694 : William and Mary)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>8 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1694]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Place of publication from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>With marginal notes.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>East India Company --  Charters --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="charter">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:35894:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>A <hi>CHARTER</hi> of Regulations to the <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Company, by Their Sacred Majeſties King <hi>WILLIAM</hi> and Queen <hi>MARY,</hi> under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> Dated the 28th. of <hi>September,</hi> 1694.</head>
            <div type="preamble">
               <pb n="1" facs="tcp:35894:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <opener>
                  <signed>
                     <hi>WILLIAM</hi> and <hi>MARY,</hi> King and Queen of <hi>England,</hi> &amp;c.</signed>
                  <salute>To the Governour and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany of Merchants, Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> &amp;c. Greeting. </salute>
               </opener>
               <p>Whereas by our Charter, Dated the 7th. <hi>October,</hi> 1693. We did appoint Sir <hi>Thomas Cooke, Francis Tyſſen</hi> Eſq; <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to be a Body Corporate and Politick, by the Name of the Governour and Company of Merchants of <hi>London,</hi> Trad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the <hi>Eaſt-Indies.</hi> under the <hi>Proviſoes</hi> therein mentioned. and did grant them ſeveral Liberties, Powers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> wherein is the <hi>Proviſo</hi> fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing of ſeveral Directions, <hi>&amp;c. viz.</hi> which if the Company don't conform unto if made before the 29th. <hi>Sept.</hi> 1694, and put under the great Seal, then We may make void theſe Preſents,
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:35894:2"/> and the Powers and things herein contained, to ceaſe and be void.</p>
               <p>And whereas by Our other Charter of the 11th. <hi>Nov.</hi> laſt, ſeveral Regulations, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> are preſcribed purſuant to that <hi>Proviſo.</hi> and alſo the following clauſe, obliging the Company to act according to ſuch Orders, Regulations, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as we ſhould make and put under Our Great Seal before the 29th. of <hi>Sept.</hi> 1694. Or elſe to be liable to have this Charter, and that of the 7th. <hi>October</hi> determined, and the Powers and Grants therein contained,</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>NOW KNOW YEE,</hi> That in purſuance of the ſaid two <hi>Proviſoes,</hi>
                  <pb n="3" facs="tcp:35894:2"/> And by vertue of what o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therwayes we may lawfully put in execution, We do by this Writing under our great Seal, by Advice of our Privy Counc<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> Order and Direct, That every Perſon qualified to Vote by our laſt Charter, or otherwiſe in a General or other Court, to be hereafter holden by the Company, ſhall before admittance to give in ſuch Votes, take an Oath before the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernour, or Deputy, or any one of the Committees. if required by any Member of the Company having 1<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <hi>l.</hi> Stock in his own Right, and not in Truſt.) That he or the ſo deſiring to Vote is then really intituled to ſo much Stock for his or her own Uſe and Right, and not in Truſt, as qualifies them to give in the Votes they deſire.</p>
               <p>Which Oath the Governour, Deputy, or any of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittees, are required to ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſter. Every Perſon not taking ſuch Oath, ſhall not be ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to give any Vote, nor their Votes be of any avail. None to be Free but Subjects Natural Born or Indenized. Every Perſon who by plura<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity of Votes ſhall be Elected Governour, Deputy, or of the Committee, ſhall before his being, or acting as ſuch, take an Oath in the General Court before the Governour, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> that at the time of his Electi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on and taking his Oath, he is intituled in his own right and not in truſt, to ſo much Stock as qualifies him for ſuch Election.</p>
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:35894:3"/>
               <p>Which Oath the ſaid Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, or Deputy, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> are required to adminiſter. And if ſuch Perſon do not take the ſame, his Election ſhall be void, and the Court ſhall proceed to a new Election, according to the Directions in this and the laſt Charter. No Perſon or Perſons that is or ſhall be Choſen Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, or Deputy of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany, ſhall continue in their places for more than two Years together. And no Perſon that hath ſerved therein two years to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether, ſhall be capable of being re-elected till two years after. If above ſixteen of the laſt years Committee-men be new Choſen at the next An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nual Election, the Supernu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>meraries who have the few<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſt Votes, their Election ſhall be void, and others choſe in their ſtead, ſo that at leaſt Eight new ones ſhall be E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lected. And whereas by the Charter of the 11th. <hi>Nov.</hi> 1693. We did Order, That the ſaid Governour and Company ſhould not Licence any Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon to Trade, or Ship to Sail, into or from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies</hi> on private Account, on pain of making void the laſt two Charters.</p>
               <p>Now we do hereby direct, That the ſaid Governour and Company may Licence the Commanders and Mari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners of their Ships, to trade in ſuch Commodi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, and to ſuch a value as a General Court ſhall allow of, and not otherwiſe.
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:35894:3"/> Due Entries being made thereof, and the Duties paid at the <hi>Cuſtom-Houſe,</hi> before the Landing, notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding the ſaid Charter.</p>
               <p>And whereas by the ſaid Charter we Ordered the ſaid Governour and Company Yearly to Export 100000 <hi>l.</hi> worth of Goods of <hi>Engliſh</hi> Manufacture, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> To the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>nd the Truth there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of may appear, We do hereby Order them to give <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> unto Us, in Our Privy Council, in the Month of <hi>Auguſt</hi> Yearly, a true Account fairly writ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten under the Governour or Deputies Hand of the Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture, Quantity, Value and Coſt of ſuch Goods Export<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Yearly. And from what place. And Oath made thereof by the Proper Officers of the Company. And We do hereby Order, that none of the Goods ſo Exported ſhall be again Landed in <hi>England,</hi> or carried elſe-where than within the Limits of the Companies Charter.</p>
               <p>If any Six or more of the Adventurers, having each 1000 <hi>l.</hi> or more, in his own Right, and not in Truſt, and qualified to Vote by the laſt Charter, ſhall at any time hereafter by Writing under their Hands, delivered to, or left for the Governour, or De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puty, at the <hi>East-India-Houſe,</hi> Requeſt a General Court may be called. The Governour, or Deputy, ſhall within Eight Days af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Summons a General Court accordingly. Which, or any other, ſhall not be broken up without Conſent of the Ma<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ority of the preſent Members capa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble to Vote.
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:35894:4"/> All private Committees of the Company ſhall be Cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen by the General Court. No Governour, Deputy, nor any of the Committees, ſhall Lend any of the Companies Money, unleſs previouſly Authoriz<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by the General Court. No Goods of the Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies ſhall be delivered to a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Perſon, till the Money be actually paid for the ſame, or Security given to the Companies Satisfaction. No Court of Committees, nor any Members of the ſaid Company, ſhall by any Agreement bind the General Stock of the Company, for Receiving or Delivering Stock, without leave of a General Court. The Companies Caſh ſhall be entirely kept in Effective Money within their own Houſe. And always be in the Cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy of Three at leaſt of the Committees of the Treaſury. And by them iſſued out to the Caſhire, as the Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies Occaſions require. No Sum of Money ſhall be allowed on the Companies Account, but where it ſhall appear when, to whom and for what it has been paid; Except only where the Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral Court ſhall previouſly Authourize any to diſpoſe thereof without Account.</p>
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:35894:4"/>
               <p>The Company notwithſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Clauſe afore-recited of the Late King <hi>Charles</hi>'s Charter, Dated the Third of <hi>April,</hi> 1561. Shall after two Years hence, In Caſe We ſhall require the ſame in Writing, make preſent payment of their Cuſtoms, due on Goods by them im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported, and be allowed Diſcount of Four Pounds Ten Shillings <hi>per Cent. per Annum,</hi> in Lieu of the ſaid two Six Months, and Six Pounds Five Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings <hi>per Cent.</hi> on Additional Duties, in Lieu of the Four Three Months allow'd by Act of Parliament. If the ſaid Charters of the 7th. <hi>October,</hi> and 11th. <hi>Nov.</hi> or any other Charters of the Companies, or theſe preſents, or the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinuance thereof in whole or part, ſhall not be profitable to Us or Our Realm. Then after Three Years warning, all the ſaid Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters ſhall be determined and Void.
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:35894:5"/> And the ſaid Governour and Company ſhall no longer continue a Corporation.</p>
               <p>The Governour and Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny ſhall, by Writing, under their Common Seal, to be Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proved of by Our Attorney or Sollicitor General, declare their Acceptance of and Submiſſion to the two Laſt, and this preſent Charter. And in Default thereof, not Act as a Corporation.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="charter_proper">
               <pb n="1" facs="tcp:35894:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <opener>
                  <signed>WILLIAM and MARY, By the Grace of God King and Queen of <hi>England, Scotland, France,</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> Defenders of the Faith, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </signed>
                  <salute> To the Governour and Company of Merchants of <hi>London,</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> and to all others to whom theſe Preſents ſhall come Greeting.</salute>
               </opener>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whereas</hi> in and by a certain Charter, or Letters Patents, under our Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing date at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> the Seventh day of <hi>October</hi> now laſt paſt, We did make, conſtitute, ordain, declare and appoint Sir <hi>Thomas Cooke</hi> Knt. and one of the Alder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men of our City of <hi>London, Francis Tyſſen</hi> Eſq; <hi>George</hi> Earl of <hi>Berkeley,</hi> and divers other perſons therein named and deſcribed, ſhould be a body Corporate and Politick, in Deed and in Name, by the Name of the Governour and Company of Merchants of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> under, and ſubject to the Proviſoes and Conditions, and upon the Terms therein mentioned, and we did thereby give and grant unto the ſaid Governour and Company, and their Succeſſors ſeveral Liberties, Powers, Priviledges and Immunities, in which ſaid Charter or Letters Patents, there is, amongſt other things therein contained, a Clauſe or Proviſo in the Words, or to the effect following, that is to ſay, <hi>Provided</hi> always, and upon condition nevertheleſs, and Our expreſs Will and Meaning is, that if the ſaid Governour and Company of Merchants of <hi>London,</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> and their Succeſſors, do not accept of, and from time to time, and at all times hereafter, Act according to, and put in due and effectual Execution, and ſubmit and conform in all things unto ſuch orders, directions, additions, alterations, reſtrictions and qualifications relating to the conſtitution, continuance, determination, rights, powers or priviledges of the ſaid Company, or the Government thereof, or of the ſaid Governour and Company, or the encourage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, management. regulation or advancement of Trade, or of the preſent or future Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company, or con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning any future Subſcriptions to be made by way of increaſe or addition to the Joynt-Stock, or for aſcertaining the true values of the ſaid Joynt-Stock, at and during the times of any ſuch future Subſcrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, which, and as We, Our Heirs, or Succeſſors, by the Advice of Our or Their Privy Council, ſhall from time to time, at any time before the Nine and Twentieth day of <hi>September,</hi> which ſhall be in the Year One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety and Four, think fit to make, in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cert, limit, direct, appoint or expreſs in or by any further or other Charter, Letters Patents, or other Writing or Inſtrument under Our or Their Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> Then, and in each and every of the Caſes aforeſaid, it ſhall and may be lawful to and for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors by Letters Patents, under Our or Their Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> to determine, revoke and make void theſe Preſents, and the Grant hereby made, and from and immediately
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:35894:2"/> after the paſſing of ſuch Letters Patents of revocation or determi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> Theſe Preſents, and all the Powers, Priviledges, Grants and other things herein contained ſhall ceaſe, determine, and be abſolutely void to all intents and purpoſes, any thing to the contrary notwithſtanding. And where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>as, in and by one other Charter, or Letters Patents, under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing date at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> the Eleventh day of <hi>November</hi> now laſt paſt, divers orders, directions, additions, alte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rations, reſtrictions, regulations, qualifications, and other matters and things are contained and preſcribed, purſuant to the ſaid <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſo</hi> in the ſaid firſt Charter, and therein is alſo contained a Clauſe or Proviſo in the Words, or to the effect following, that is to ſay, <hi>Provided alwayes,</hi> and upon condition nevertheleſs, and our expreſs Will and Meaning is, and we do hereby order, direct and appoint, and the ſaid Governour and Company do hereby agree, That if ſaid Governour and Company of Merchants of <hi>London</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> and their Succeſſors, do not accept of, and from time to time, and at all times hereafter Act according to, and put in due and effectual Execution, and ſubmit and conform in all things unto, as well all and every the orders, directions, additions, al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terations, reſtrictions, qualifications, matters and things herein before expreſſed, as alſo all and every ſuch further, and other orders, di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rections, additions, alterations, reſtrictions and qualifications relating to the Conſtitution, Continuance, Determination, Rights, Powers or Priviledges of the ſaid Company, or the Government thereof, or of the ſaid Governour and Company, or the Encouragement, Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nagement, Regulation or Advancement of Trade, or of the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent or future Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company, or concerning any future Subſcriptions to be made by way of increaſe or addition to the Joynt-Stock, or for aſcertaining the true values of the ſaid Joynt-Stock, at and during the times of any ſuch future ſubſcripti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, which, and as We, Our Heirs or Succeſſors, by the Advice of Our or their Privy Council, ſhall from time to time, at any time before the Nine and twentieth day of <hi>September,</hi> which ſhall be in the Year One thouſand Six hundred Ninety four, think fit to make, incert, limit, direct, appoint or expreſs in or by any fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther or other Charter, Letters Patents, or other Writing or In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrument under Our or their Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> then and in each and every of the Caſes aforeſaid, it ſhall and may be lawful to and for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, by Letters Patents under Our or their Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> to determine, revoke and make void, as well theſe Preſents, and the Grant hereby made, as alſo the ſaid Charter or Letters Patents, bearing date the Seventh day of <hi>October</hi> laſt paſt, herein before mentioned, and all and every, or any the matters and things therein and herein contained; and from and immediately after the paſſing of ſuch Letters Patents of Revo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation or Determination under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> as well theſe Preſents, as alſo the ſaid Charter or Letters Patents, bearing Date the Seventh day of <hi>October</hi> laſt paſt and all the Powers, Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viledges, Grants, and other things therein and herein contained, ſhall ceaſe, determine, and be abſolutely void to all intents and purpoſes, any thing to the contrary notwithſtanding, As in and by the ſaid ſeveral Letters Patents, relation being thereunto reſpectively had, may more fully and at large appear. <hi>NOW KNOW YEE,</hi> That by vertue and in purſuance of the ſaid two <hi>Proviſoes</hi> in the ſaid Charters and Letters Patents mentioned, and by vertue of all other Powers, Wayes and Means, which We
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:35894:2"/> have, or can, or lawfully may make uſe of, or put in Execution, We do by this Writing or Inſtrument under Our Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> by the Advice of our Privy Council, Order and Direct, That every Perſon who by having One Thouſand Pounds, or more, in the Stock of the ſaid Company, is or ſhall be by vertue of our ſaid laſt Charter, or otherwiſe qualified or intituled to give one or more Vote or Votes in any General or other Court to be at any time or times hereafter holden for the ſaid Company, ſhall at the time of holding of every ſuch General or other Court, and before ſuch perſons ſhall be admitted to give any Vote or Votes in any ſuch Court, take an Oath before the Governour of the ſaid Company or his Deputy, or ſome one or more of the Twenty four Committees of the ſaid Company then preſent, if thereunto re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired by any Members of the ſaid Company then preſent, having One Thouſand pound or more, in the Stock of the ſaid Company in his own Right, and not in Truſt for any other, That he or ſhe ſo offering or deſiring to give any Vote or Votes in any ſuch Court, than is really and <hi>bona fide</hi> Intereſted in and Entituled unto ſo much of the Stock of the ſaid Company for his or her own Uſe, and in his or her own Right, and not in Truſt for any other Perſon or Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons as doth Entitle him or her according to the Directions and Qualifications mentioned in Our ſaid laſt Charter, unto ſuch Vote or Number of Votes in a General, or other Court, which he or ſhe then does or ſhall Give in, or Offer or Deſire to Give, (which <hi>Oath</hi> the Governour or his Deputy, or ſome one or more of the Twenty Four Committees of the ſaid Company Then preſent, ſhall, and are hereby Authorized and Required, from time to time, to Adminiſter accordingly). <hi>And if</hi> any ſuch Perſon or Perſons ſo Required to take ſuch Oath, ſhall Refuſe or Neglect to take the ſame, Then he or ſhe ſo Neglecting or Refuſing, ſhall not be Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted, nor have any Capacity to Give any Vote or Votes in any ſuch General, or other Court, Nor ſhall any ſuch Vote or Votes be of any avail, Any thing in the ſaid recited Charters, or either of them, or other matter or thing whatſoever to the contrary notwithſtanding. And We do hereby further, in like manner, Order and Direct, That no Perſon ſhall be admitted to the Free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of the ſaid Company, that at the time of ſuch Admiſſion ſhall not be a Natural born Subject of this Realm, or Naturalized or Indenized. And we do hereby further, in like manner, Order and Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rect, That every Perſon who ſhall by Plurality of Votes be Elected Governour or Deputy Governour, or any of the Twenty Four Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittees of the ſaid Company, ſhall before he take upon him to be, or to Act as Governour, Deputy, or one of the Twenty Four Committees, take an Oath in the General Court of the Company, before the Governour, or Deputy, or one or more of the Twenty Four Committees of the ſaid Company, (not being a party con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerned) That ſuch Perſon ſo Elected Governour, or Deputy Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernour, or one of the Committee at the time of ſuch Election, or Giving of Votes as aforeſaid, was, and at the time of taking ſuch Oath is, really and <hi>bona fide</hi> Intereſted in, and Entituled unto, ſo much of the Stock of the ſaid Company in his own Right, and to his own proper Uſe, and not in Truſt for any other, As by, and according to Our ſaid laſt Charter, Doth Qualifie and Capacitate ſuch Perſon or Perſons to be Elected Governour or Deputy Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, or one of the Committees of the ſaid Company reſpectively, Which Oath the ſaid Governour, Deputy Governour, or any one of the ſaid Twenty Four Committees (not being a party Concerned
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:35894:3"/> in that preſent queſtion) is, And are hereby reſpectively, from time to time Authorized, and Required, to Adminiſter accordingly; and If ſuch Perſon or Perſons ſo Elected, into any the ſaid Offices or Places reſpectively, ſhall Refuſe or Neglect to take the ſame, Then the Election, and Votes given for the Election of every ſuch Perſon ſo Refuſing ſhall be void. <hi>And</hi> the ſaid Company ſhall from time to time proceed to a New Election, according to the Direction and Qualifications in this and our ſaid laſt Charter, as if the ſaid Refuſer or Refuſers had never been Choſen, And as if no Votes had been given for ſuch his Choice and Election. <hi>And We do hereby further, in like manner, Order and Direct,</hi> That no Perſon or Perſons that Now is, or hereafter ſhall be Choſen Governour, or Deputy Governour of the ſaid Company, ſhall continue in the Office or Place of Governour, or Deputy Governour, or either of them for more than Two Years together; And that no Perſon or Perſons that ſhall have ſerved in both or either of the ſaid Offices of Governour, or Deputy Governour of the ſaid Company by the ſpace of Two Years, together, ſhall be Choſen, or Capable of being Choſen, into either of the ſaid two Offices or Places, within the ſpace of Two Years next after the end of the laſt of thoſe Two Years wherein he ſerved either as Governour, or Deputy Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour. <hi>And we do alſo hereby, in like manner, further Order and Direct,</hi> That the Twenty Four Committees of the ſaid Company ſhall be Yearly Choſen; and if at ſuch Election, more than Sixteen of thoſe for the laſt Year ſhall be Choſen, The Election of ſo many of them as are above the Number of Sixteen, and have the feweſt Voices, ſhall be Void, and others Choſe in their ſtead, ſo that there ſhall be Yearly, at leaſt, Eight that were not of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee the precedeing year. <hi>And whereas,</hi> in and by the ſaid laſt mentioned Charter, bearing Date the Eleventh day of <hi>November,</hi> in the Fifth Year of Our Reign, It is provided, <hi>And</hi> We did thereby Order and Appoint, That the ſaid Governour and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany of Merchants of <hi>London</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> or their Succeſſors, ſhould not at any time then after, Licence or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit any Perſon or Perſons whatſoever, to Trade or Traffique, or any Ship or Ships, to Sail or paſs into, or from any part of the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> on any private Account whatſoever, and that if any ſuch Licence, or Permiſſion, ſhould be granted contrary to Our ſaid Order and Appointment therein before declared, That then, and In each ſuch Caſe, as well the ſaid Laſt mentioned Charter, or Letters Patents, as alſo the ſaid Letters Patents bearing Date the ſaid Seventh day of <hi>October</hi> laſt paſt, and all and every the Powers, Grants, Matters and Things in both the ſaid Letters Patents contained, ſhould Ceaſe, Determine, and be utterly Void to all Intents and Purpoſes, Any thing to the Contrary notwithſtanding. <hi>Now We do hereby Order and Direct,</hi> That the ſaid Governour and Company of Merchants of <hi>London,</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> and their Succeſſors, May at any time hereafter Licence, and permit, any Commanders, Officers and Seamen, which from time to time, or at any time hereafter, ſhall be Employed by the ſaid Company, in the Ships of, or belonging to, or in the Service of, the ſaid mompany, and ſet out upon the ſaid Companies Account onely, to Trade and Traffique in, and to Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port in ſuch Ships, from any part of the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> for and upon the Account of ſuch Commanders, Officers or Seamen, only ſuch Commodities and Goods, and ſuch proportion thereof, as ſhall be from time to time permitted, and allowed of, by the Majority of Votes at a General Court of the ſaid Company for the time being,
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:35894:3"/> and not otherwiſe; Due Entries being made thereof, and the Duties Due for the ſame, being paid, or ſecured, at, or in, our Cuſtom-Houſe of the place where the ſame ſhall be Imported, before the Landing thereof; The ſaid laſt-mentioned <hi>Proviſoe,</hi> Direction, or Appointment, contained in the ſaid laſt-mentioned Charter, to the Contrary notwithſtanding. <hi>And Whereas,</hi> We did alſo in, and by, the ſaid laſt-mentioned Charter, or Letters Patents, Order and Appoint. That the ſaid Governour and Company of Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chants of <hi>London,</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> and their Succeſſors, ſhould Yearly, and every Year, During the Continuance of the ſaid Joint-Stock, Export, and Carry, to the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> ſo many Goods of the Growth, Product, or Manufacture of this Our King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of <hi>England,</hi> as ſhould Amount to the Value of One Hundred Thouſand Pound at the leaſt. <hi>To the End therefore,</hi> That the Truth and Certainty thereof may be made to appear to Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, <hi>We do hereby, in like manner, Order and Direct,</hi> That the ſaid Governour and Company, for the time being, and their Succeſſors, Do and Shall give in, and deliver, unto Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, in Our, or Their Privy Council, Yearly, and every Year, in the Month of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> A True Account, or Inventory, fairly Written and Signed by the Governour, or Deputy Governour, of the ſaid Company for the time being, Containing the Nature, Quantity, Quality, Value and Prime Coſt, of all ſuch Goods of the Growth, Product or Manufacture of this Our King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of <hi>England,</hi> as in the laſt precedeing Year have been Exported, and Carried to the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> on the ſaid Companies Account, Together with the Place, Town, or Port, from whence the ſaid Goods were Exported to the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> And, That Oath be made of the Truth of ſuch Account or Inventory, by the proper Officers, or Servants, of the ſaid Company, concerned in ſuch Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portation. <hi>And We do hereby further, in like manner, Order and Direct,</hi> That None of the ſaid Goods, or Commodities, ſo Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported, ſhall be again Landed in Our Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> Domi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion of <hi>Wales,</hi> or Town of <hi>Berwick</hi> upon <hi>Tweed,</hi> or be carried to any other Countrey or Place, but into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> or ſome place within the Limits, or Bounds, of the ſaid Companies Charter. <hi>And We do hereby, in like manner, further Order and Direct,</hi> That in Caſe any Six, or more, of the Members of the ſaid Company, who ſhall then each have in the Stock of the ſaid Company, One Thouſand Pounds, or more, for his own Uſe, and in his own Right, and not in Truſt, or for any other, and qualified to Vote in a General, or other Court of the ſaid Company, as by the ſaid laſt-mentioned Charter is Directed, ſhall at any time or times hereafter, by any Writing under their Hands, to be delivered unto, or Left for the Governour, or Deputy Governour, of the ſaid Company for the time being, at the <hi>Eaſt-In<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ia-Houſe,</hi> or other uſual place of Meeting of the ſaid Company, Requeſt the ſaid Governour, or Deputy Governour, to Call a General Court of the ſaid Company, That then, and ſo often, the ſaid Governour, or Deputy Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, ſhall within Eight Days next after ſuch Writing ſhall be Delivered, or Left as aforeſaid, Summon a General Court accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingly; And that the ſame being ſo Aſſembled, as alſo any other General Court, which ſhall be at any time hereafter Aſſembled, ſhall not be broken up, or Diſſolved, without the Conſent of the Majority of the Members of the ſaid Company then preſent, and Capable to Vote in ſuch General Court as aforeſaid. <hi>And We do hereby further, in like manner, Order and Direct,</hi> That all and every
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:35894:4"/> Private Committees of the ſaid Company, ſhall from time to time, and at all times hereafter, be Choſen and appointed by the Majority of a General Court of the ſaid Company, and not by the Court of Committees of the ſaid Company. <hi>And We do hereby, in like manner, further Order and Direct,</hi> That the Governour, Deputy Governour, and Committees of the ſaid Company for the time being, or any of them, ſhall not Lend, Nor ſhall it be in the Power of them, or any of them, to Lend any Money of or belonging to the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany, to any Perſon or Perſons whatſoever, unleſs previouſly Enabled or Authorized to do the ſame by the Majority of the Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral Court. <hi>And further we do, in like manner, Order and Direct,</hi> That No Goods whatſoever, of or belonging to the ſaid Company, ſhall be delivered to any Perſon or Perſons whatſoever, until the Money be actually paid for the ſame, or ſuch Security given, as ſhall be approved of by a Majority of Votes, in a Court of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittees of the ſaid Company. <hi>And We do alſo hereby, in like man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, Order and Direct,</hi> That no Court of Committees of the ſaid Company, or any Member or Members of the ſaid Company, Do, or ſhall at any time or times hereafter, Make or Enter into any Contract, Article or Agreement, with any Perſon or Perſons what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever, whereby to Oblige, or by means or reaſon whereof, the General Stock of the ſaid Company, or any part thereof, ſhall or may be Obliged or Bound, either for Receiving or Delivering of Stock at a Price Agreed on, without Leave firſt had or obtained in that behalf, by a Majority of Votes in a General Court of the ſaid Company. <hi>And We do hereby, in like manner, further Order and Direct,</hi> That the Caſh of and belonging to the ſaid Company, ſhall from time to time, and at all times hereafter, be entirely kept in Effective Money, within the Companies Houſe in <hi>Leaden-hall-Street, London,</hi> Or in ſuch other Houſe or Place where the ſaid Company ſhall meet, and ſit for the Diſpatch of the Companies Buſineſs. <hi>And further,</hi> That the Money, and Caſh of the ſaid Company for the time being, ſo to be kept as aforeſaid, ſhall always be and Remain in the Cuſtody of Three at leaſt of the Committees of the Treaſury, of, or belonging to, the ſaid Company for the time being, to be by them iſſued out to the Caſhier of the ſaid Company for the time being, in ſuch Sums as the Companies Oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſions ſhall or may from time to time Require. <hi>And We do hereby, in like manner, further Order and Direct,</hi> That No Sum or Sums of Money whatſoever ſhall be allowed by or upon the Account of the ſaid Company, but in ſuch Caſe, where it ſhall appear when, to whom, and for what, ſuch Sum or Sums of Money was, or were paid; <hi>Except</hi> in ſuch Caſes where, by Authority of a General Court of the ſaid Company, any Committee, or Member or Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers of the ſaid Company, ſhall be previouſly Authorized, and Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>powered to Diſpoſe of the ſame without account. <hi>And whereas,</hi> Our Late Royal Uncle King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, in and by certain Letters Patents under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing Date the Third day of <hi>April,</hi> in the Thirteenth Year of His Reign, Did for Him, His Heirs and Succeſſors, Grant to the ſaid Governour and Company of Merchants of <hi>London,</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> and their Succeſſors, That when, and as often as any Cuſtom, Poundage, Subſidy, or other Duties ſhould be due and payable unto the ſaid Late King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, His Heirs or Succeſſors, for any Goods, Wares or Merchandizes whatſoever, to be returned out of, or from, any the Iſlands, Ports, Havens, Cities, Towns or Places therein mentioned, unto the Port of <hi>London,</hi> or
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:35894:4"/> any of the Havens, Creeks, Members or Places to the ſame Port belonging, That the Cuſtomers, and all other Officers for the time being, of the ſaid Late King, His Heirs or Succeſſors, for or con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning the Receipt of Cuſtom, Poundage, Subſidy or other Duties, to whom it ſhould or might appertain, ſhould upon the Requeſt of the Governour and Company of the ſaid Merchants of <hi>London,</hi> Trading to the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> or any their Agents, Factors or Aſſigns, Give unto the ſaid Governour and Company, their Agents, Factors or Aſſigns Six Months time for the payment of the one half, and after Thoſe Six Months ended, Other Six Months for the Payment of the other half of their ſaid Cuſtoms, Poundage, or other Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidies or Duties, Receiving good and ſufficient Bond with Surety, to the uſe of the ſaid late King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, his Heirs and Succeſſors, for the true payment of the ſame accordingly, And up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Receipt of the ſaid Bond with Surety, from time to time to Give unto the ſaid Governour and Company of Merchants of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> for the time being, their Agents, Factors or Aſſigns, Their Cocquets, or other Warrants, to take out and receive on Land the ſame Goods, Wares and Merchan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>di<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>es, by vertue thereof, without any Diſturbance. <hi>And whereas Wee</hi> Think it Requiſite for our Service, that ſome Alteration be made in that Matter, <hi>We do therefore by theſe preſents, in like man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, Order and Direct,</hi> That the ſaid Governour and Company of Merchants of <hi>London,</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies</hi> and their Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors, Do and ſhall, from and after, the end of Two Years com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mencing from the Date hereof, (In Caſe We, Our Heirs or Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors, by any Writing under Our, or their Royal Sign Manual, ſhall require the ſame) Make preſent payment of all the Cuſtoms, Subſidies, Additional and other Duties, Due and payable to Us, Our Heirs or Succeſſors, for ſuch Goods and Commodities as after the end of the ſaid Two Years ſhall be Imported into Our Port of <hi>London,</hi> or any the Havens, Creeks, Members or Places to the ſame Port belonging, by or upon the Account, or in the Name of the ſaid Company, And in conſideration of ſuch preſent payment, the ſaid Governour and Company, and their Succeſſors, ſhall be allowed to Deduct and Diſcount after the Rate of Four Pounds Ten Shillings <hi>per Cent.</hi> for a Year, for all the ſaid Cuſtoms and Duties ſo paid, in Lieu and Recompence for the two Six Months, given them by the ſaid Charter for payment thereof. <hi>And ſhall alſo</hi> be further allowed for all the Additional Impoſitions and Duties now payable by the ſaid Company, (other than the Duties of Tonnage and Poundage) after the rate of Six Pounds and Five Shillings <hi>per Cent.</hi> by way of Diſcount for preſent pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, in Lieu and Recompence for the Four Three Months al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed for payment thereof, by the ſeveral Acts of Parliament by which the ſaid Duties are granted. <hi>And We do hereby, in like man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, Order and Direct,</hi> That if it ſhall appear to us Our Heirs or Succeſſors, That the ſaid two Charters, or Letters Patents, bear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Date the Seventh day of <hi>October,</hi> and the Eleventh of <hi>No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vember</hi> now laſt paſt, or any other Charters, or Letters Patents, heretofore made, or Granted to the ſaid Governour and Company of Merchants of <hi>London,</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> or theſe Preſents, any or either of them, or the continuance of them, any or either of them, in the whole, or in any part thereof, ſhall not be profitable to Us, Our Heirs, or Succeſſors, or to this Our Realm, That then, and from thenceforth, upon and after Three Years warning to be given to the ſaid Company by Us, Our Heirs or
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:35894:5"/> Succeſſors, under Our or their Privy Seal or Sign Manual, The ſaid ſeveral Letters Patents, bearing Date the ſaid Seventh day of <hi>Octo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber,</hi> and Eleventh day of <hi>November</hi> now laſt paſt, and other the ſaid former Charters or Letters Patents, and the Regulations in theſe Preſents contained, and every of them, ſhall Ceaſe, be Void, and Determined, to all Intents, Conſtructions and Purpoſes. And the ſaid Governour and Company of Merchants of <hi>London,</hi> Trad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> from and after the end of the ſaid three Years, ſhall not Continue to be, nor ſhall Act as a Corporation, or Body Politick, but ſhall be wholly Determined; Any thing therein or herein contained to the contrary in any wiſe notwithſtanding. <hi>And We do hereby alſo, in like manner, Order and Direct,</hi> That the ſaid Governour and Company of Merchants of <hi>London,</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> Do and ſhall, before the Firſt day of <hi>December</hi> next Enſuing, by an Inſtrument in Writing, under their Common Seal, to be approved of by our Attorney, or Solicitor General, Declare their Acceptance of, and Submiſſion unto the ſaid Charters of the Seventh of <hi>October,</hi> and Eleventh of <hi>November</hi> laſt paſt, and all and every the Regulations, Matters and Things therein and in either of them contained; And alſo their Acceptance of, and Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion unto theſe Preſents, and the ſeveral Matters and Things therein contained. And if they ſhall Refuſe, or Neglect, ſo to do, that Then the ſaid Governour and Company of Merchants of <hi>London,</hi> Trading to the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> from and after the ſaid Firſt day of <hi>December</hi> next, ſhall not continue to be, nor ſhall Act as a Corporation, or Body Politick, but ſhall be wholly Determined, any thing to the contrary Notwithſtanding. <hi>In VVitneſs</hi> whereof, <hi>VVe have</hi> Cauſed theſe Our Letters to be made Patents. <hi>VVitneſs</hi> Our Selves at <hi>VVeſtminſter,</hi> the Eight and Twentieth Day of <hi>September,</hi> in the Sixth Year of Our Reign.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>
                     <hi>per ipſos <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="4 letters">
                           <desc>••••</desc>
                        </gap>m &amp; Reginam.</hi>
                  </signed>
                  <signed>Pigott.</signed>
               </closer>
               <pb facs="tcp:35894:5"/>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
